# BARTHOLOMEW EGUOBA

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER





Surulere, Lagos. Nigeria

github.com/retrong

+234 704 850 4769

www.linkedin.com/in/retrong/

## PROFILE

Logical and result driven Web developer dedicated to building and optimizing user-focused web applications for customers and various business objectives. Creative and research-driven when crafting effective web applications and platforms to propel competitive advantage and revenue growth.

## SKILLS

- Html
- CSS
- SCSS/SASS
- Javascript
- ReactJS
- Graphql
- Bootstrap/Tailwind
- Agile Methodology
- Critical Thinking
- Creativity

## EDUCATION

### **BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE**

University of Benin Benin city, Edo, Nigeria

2017 - 2022

- > Conducted tutorials for colleagues and junior colleagues
- Member of Google DeveloperStudent Club(GDSC) Benin

## EXPERIENCE

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Black Shakara (Full-Time)

March 2022 - Present

- Implemented innovative features and enhancements to the company's web platform, resulting in a more structured and userfriendly UI
- Improved user experience and performance modification to an existing payroll package; then worked with backend engineer to improve seamless data transfer between endpoints
- Assist in code refactoring and optimization, making the platform more user-friendly and archived a 30% improvement in load time
- Participate in daily stand-ups and sprint planning, ensuring timely task deliveries

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Ingressive For Good (I4G)

(Part-Time)

September 2022- November 2022

- Volunteered on a cross-functional team to develop and implement
   a P2P e-commerce web application using React and Redux
- Executed responsive design principles using Tailwind and CSS, resulting in a seamless user experience across devices; decreased bounce rate by 25% and increased mobile conversions by 40%
- Conducted cross-browser compatibility testing to ensure consistent performance across different browsers and provided support to the 10+ developers on my team

> Joined college basketball team and played inter-faculty competitions

## SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE

Stadium High School Hogan Bassey Cres, Lagos, Nigeria 2009 - 2015

- > Senior member of Jet(science) Club and assistant head of Red Cross
- > Lab prefect for Chemistry laboratory
- > Football Silver Medalist
- > 100 & 400 meters athletics finalist
- > Cowbellpedia Maths competition state finalist

• Integrated front-end code with backend APIs to enable real-time data updates and enhance user interactivity, resulting in seamless data transfer from the front end to the backend.

#### **DEVELOPER INTERN**

Edo Innovation Hub (Intern)
59 C, ICE Road, Off Wire Rd, Benin City
April 2021 - August 2021

- Worked with Senior Developers to develop and improve upon my programming skills while building a mockup of the EdoJobs clientside pages
- I took classes on the AWS cloud practitioner program to equip myself with the knowledge of Cloud Computing
- Handled supervision and technical issues relating to software installation and systems updates in the hub during computer appreciation programs
- Assisted in the development and implementation of new features on the web applications using HTML, CSS, and Javascript

## REFERENCES

### MR PRECIOUS

Lead Developer and Supervisor



Edo Innovation Hub



info@edoinnovates.com

### MR CHIBUIKE

Lead Developer and Tutor



Edo Innovation Hub



info@edoinnovates.com

### MR VALENTINE AGBAWO

CEO



Black Shakara



blackshakara@gmail.com

## LANGUAGES

**ENGLISH** 



### **PROJECTS**

- Developed and maintained a fast-food delivery web application
- Integrated front-end code with backend APIs for an E-Voting web application to enable real-time data updates and enhance user interactivity for my school project
- Pioneered responsive design principles while building a coffee web application using HTML, CSS, and JS
- Built a mockup page using data from spaceX API, showing flight time, rockets, and astronauts' data
- Built a mockup landing page for a bank app and optimized website performance, resulting in a 25% decrease in page load time
- Volunteered in designing and implementation of an NFT card UI and worked on improving the UI of Diginosys project
- Designed and developed a QRcode generator using Javascript that generates a different QRcode on every input by the user